Brandon Joel Gonzalez - Page 1

Brandon Joel Gonzalez - Curriculum Vitae

Email: bgonzale@andrew.cmu.edu — Personal Website: brandon-joel-gonzalez.github.io

Career Objectives

Interested in the development of wireless embedded systems and RF engineering. Pursuing a doctorate in electrical and computer engineering, with a long-term goal of teaching and research at a university. Love of learning and helping guide others to their fullest potential.

Education

Carnegie Mellon University – College of Engineering (CIT)

- ❖ Ph.D Student in *Electrical and Computer Engineering* − August 2021 Present
 - > Research Advisor: Dr. L. Richard Carley
 - > Research Interests: wireless embedded systems, RF engineering

University of Pennsylvania – School of Engineering and Applied Science (SEAS)

- ❖ M.S.E. in *Robotics* − May 2021
- ❖ B.S.E. in *Computer Science*, minor in *Mathematics* December 2019 Cum Laude

Teaching Experience

Semesters as head TA denoted with * and semesters online denoted with ^.

- ❖ CMU − 18-429/729: *Board-Level RF Systems for IoT* − Fall 2022*
 - > Experimental laboratory course exploring RF engineering concepts, including transmission lines, antenna design, SDR, MIMO, and beamforming
- ♦ UPenn ESE450/451: ESE Senior Design Fall 2019, Spring 2020^, Fall 2020*^, Spring 2021*^
 - > Two-part senior capstone project series for students in the Electrical and Systems Engineering department and related majors
- ♦ UPenn ESE350/519: Embedded Systems Lab Fall 2020^, Spring 2021*^
 - > Advanced laboratory course covering the foundations and design of embedded systems platforms, across both hardware and software levels
- ❖ UPenn ESE190/M&TSI: Introduction to Hardware/Software Lab Spring 2019, Summer 2021*^
 - > Introductory laboratory course exploring the Arduino platform, primarily for students without engineering background
- ♦ UPenn CIS371/501: Computer Architecture Fall 2019, Spring 2020^
 - > Advanced systems course exploring design and optimization techniques in modern computer architecture, with labs in Verilog
- ♦ UPenn CIS380/548/CIT595: *Operating Systems* Fall 2019, Spring 2020*^, Summer 2020*^
 - > Advanced systems course exploring design and implementation of operating systems, primarily Unix-based, in the C programming language
- ❖ UPenn CIS240/CIT593: Introduction to Computer Systems Fall 2018, Spring 2019, Summer 2019^
 - > Introductory systems course covering topics from CMOS logic gates to architecture design to operating systems programming

Brandon Joel Gonzalez - Page 2

Research Experience

- ❖ Directional Antenna Arrays for LPWANs
 - ➤ Research (in-progress) done under the mentorship of Professor Anthony Rowe and Professor Asim Smailagic, continuing the work of Dr. Artur Balanuta in the WiSE Lab, as part of 18-843 (*Mobile and Pervasive Computing*) at CMU in Fall 2022
 - > Planning to deploy client nodes that utilize beam steering, through the use of directional antenna arrays, to access LoRaWAN gateways around CMU's campus
 - Expecting to see better coverage and less interference between clients compared to omnidirectional antennas with similar gain
 - Developing a hotspot offloading algorithm that will allow balancing of loads between gateways through network feedback
 - > Will provide a link to a video demonstration and poster at the end of the semester
- ❖ Infrastructure Sensing in Pittsburgh
 - ➤ Research done as part of 18-745 (*Rapid Prototyping of Computer Systems*) at CMU in Spring 2022
 - > Focused on developing ways to enhance public transportation in Pittsburgh by using infrastructure sensing to detect problems around the city
 - Worked on Hardware Development team, exploring a number of sensors to collect information about the state of transportation in the city
 - Used image data to detect obstacles on the road and accelerometer data to detect potholes and other bumps while driving
 - Interfaced sensors with Raspberry Pi devices
 - Set up a wireless network to stream data packets to a cloud database for offline analysis, resulting in these issues around the city being flagged on a map
 - ➤ <u>Link</u> to course final report; see section on "Infrastructure Sensing Hardware" on page 90 for my specific team's work
- Human Occupancy Detection
 - ➤ Research done under the mentorship of Professor Camillo Jose Taylor and Dr. Madhu Annapragada as part of ROBO597 (*Master's Thesis*) at UPenn from Fall 2020 to Spring 2021
 - > Sought to develop a hybrid sensor system for human occupancy detection
 - Examined a wide variety of sensors including PIR, thermopile array, and mm-wave TI devices
 - Attempted to combine sensors in order to develop an efficient, novel device that accurately counts human occupants
 - Encountered difficulties in the implementation, but learned about embedded systems, signal processing, and sensor fusion
 - ➤ <u>Link</u> to the project repository with more information, including the thesis itself and a presentation from May 2021

Brandon Joel Gonzalez - Page 3

Activities and Interests

- SEAS Orientation Peer Adviser for Class of 2022 (CIS) and Class of 2023 (CMPE)
- Head of Hardware team for <u>PennApps</u> hackathon from Spring 2019 to Spring 2021, organized with <u>Major League Hacking</u> (MLH)
- ❖ Student member of the ECE Diversity, Inclusion, and Outreach Committee
- ❖ <u>Build18</u> Officer for the 2023 Season
- ❖ 2022-23 Graduate ECE Representative of <u>TechSpark</u> Student Committee
- ❖ 2022-23 CMU Robotics Club Graduate Student Officer
- ❖ 2022-23 IEEE CMU Chapter Graduate/Research Committee Chair
- ❖ 2022-23 Officer of the Eta Kappa Nu (HKN), Sigma Chapter at Carnegie Mellon University

Awards and Recognitions

- Recipient of the 2017 <u>Penn Undergraduate Research Mentoring (PURM) Grant</u>
- ❖ Recipient of the 2018 <u>Penn Engineering Exceptional Service Award</u>
- Recipient of the 2019 <u>Littlejohn Scholars Summer Research Grant</u>
- ❖ 2019-20 <u>J.P. Eckert Fellow</u>
- ❖ 2020 inductee of the <u>CIS TA Hall of Fame</u>
- * Recipient of the <u>Summer 2020 TA Award for Excellence in Student Support with Distinction</u>
- ❖ 2021 ESE Diversity, Equity, and Inclusion Fellow
- ❖ Honorable Mention for the <u>2021 Penn Engineering Outstanding Teaching Award</u>
- Carnegie Institute of Technology Dean's Fellow
- 2022 inductee of the Eta Kappa Nu (HKN). Sigma Chapter at Carnegie Mellon University
- Selected to participate in the <u>2022 NextProf Pathfinder</u> workshop hosted by UMich and UCSD